boutique1.com 2018-11-21

# Privacy Policy

Publication Date: 25/5/2018

What does this policy cover?

This policy describes the processing of your personal data in relation to your use of this website by Boutique 1, 259a Pavilion Road, London, SW1X 0BP ("Boutique 1", "we", "us" or "our"), as the owner and operator of this website, and in connection with your interaction with us at the Boutique 1 Store ("in-store").

Boutique 1 is a "data controller". This means that we are responsible for deciding how we hold and use personal information about you.

What personal data is collected?Personal data collected from you:The following categories of personal data will be collected about you in connection with your use of the website and your interaction with us in-store, including, but not limited to, when you fill in forms on the website or whilst in-store, register to use the website:

-   Personal Identification Information: such as, your name, date of birth, gender;

-   Contact Information: such as, email address and telephone number;

-   Demographic Information: such as, postcode;

-   Preference Information: such as, information about the types of products you have viewed on the website, and information about the types of products you like or are interested in;

-   Financial information: such as, credit / debit card numbers; and

-   Your marketing preferences, including any consents you have given us.

In addition, if you contact us by phone, email or otherwise, we may keep a record of that correspondence. 

Information we collect from others:

Although we generally collect personal data directly from you, we also collect certain categories of personal data about you from other sources. In particular, financial or transaction data from payment providers in order to process a transaction.

Information we collect automatically:

We use cookies and related technologies on our websites and other web-based interfaces, our mobile website and applications. We use these technologies to understand how many users visited our sites and the pages they accessed so that we can best tailor our web services to our visitors. To this extent we may collect information such as web browser type and version, operating system, the website you came from and exit to, your IP (Internet Protocol) address, your Device ID and Mac ID your browser settings, the date and time of your visits, and details regarding your interaction with the website (including which pages, products or resources on the website you access). To learn more about our use of cookies or similar technology please check our cookies section below. 

How is your personal data used, and what is the legal basis for this use?We process your personal data for the following purposes:

Contractual Necessity:  
As required to establish and fulfill a contract with you, for example: if you make a purchase from us (this will include taking payments, and arranging the delivery or other provision of products, awards or services); communicating with you and providing customer services.

legitimate Interests:  
As required by us to pursue our own legitimate interests, in particular:

-   Creating and managing online registered accounts;

-   Monitoring any online registered accounts to prevent, investigate and/or report fraud, terrorism, misrepresentation, security incidents or crime, in accordance with applicable law;

-   Delivering tailored advertising;

-   Creating user / customer insights based on transactional behaviour segments to drive targeted direct marketing;

-   Creating user / customer insights based on demographic segments to drive targeted email direct marketing and also carrying out market research and survey

-   Communicating with you; and

-   Investigating and handling any complaints received from you about our website, or our products and services.

You can obtain further information on the legitimate interests balancing exercises which we have carried out by contacting us using the contact details provided below.

Legal Compliance:  
To ensure compliance with applicable laws and legal processes including, but not limited to, use in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory, tax, investigative purposes (including disclosure of such information in connection with legal process or litigation and to law enforcement agencies). 

Consent:  
Subject to the following, we will send you direct marketing by email, SMS, telephone, post, and online about Boutique 1 products and services which we think may be of interest to you. This will only be sent where you have given your consent to Boutique 1 during the online sign-up process or via your online account on the website or verbally in-store, or (where permissible) you have been given an opportunity to opt out. You will be able to opt-out of electronic direct marketing by clicking the unsubscribe link contained in the email itself.

Who will your personal data be shared with, and where?:

We will share your personal data with:

-   Members of our group of companies (Boutique 1 Group LLC and Boutique 1 Limited) for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice;

-   Third party service providers, who will process it on our behalf for the purposes above. Such third parties include, but are not limited to, couriers to deliver your orders, IT systems providers;

-   Government authorities and/or law enforcement officials if required for the purposes above, if mandated by law or if required for the legal protection of our own legitimate interests in compliance with applicable laws; and

-   Purchasers or prospective purchasers of all or part of our assets or our business, and their professional advisers, in connection with the purchase.

When we transfer your information to other countries, we will use, share and safeguard that information as described in this Policy. To provide some of our services, we may transfer the personal information we collect to our affiliates established in countries outside of the EEA which do not provide the same level of data protection as the country in which you reside and are not recognized by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of data protection. We only transfer personal information to these countries, with your consent or when it is necessary for the services we provide you or subject to safeguards that assure the protection of your personal information, such as European Commission approved standard contractual clauses. 

All Boutique 1 group companies throughout the world will ensure a level of data protection at least as protective as that required in the European Economic Area. We also require our agents, consultants and sub-contractors and others who are outside the European Economic Area and to whom we transfer your personal data to ensure a similar level of data protection.

For further information, including to obtain a copy of the documents used to protect your information, please contact us on dataprotection@boutique1.com.

Security of your personal data

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. 

We have also put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so. 

Updating personal data about you  
If any of the personal data that you have provided to us changes, for example if you change your email address or if you wish to cancel any request you have made of us, or if you become aware we have any inaccurate personal data about you, please let us know by sending an email to dataprotection@boutique1.com. We will not be responsible for any losses arising from any inaccurate, inauthentic, deficient or incomplete Personal Data that you provide to us.

Your Rights

You have various rights with respect to our use of your personal data: 

Access:  
You have the right to request a copy of the personal data that we hold about you. There are exceptions to this right, so that access may be denied if, for example, making the information available to you would reveal personal data about another person, or if we are legally prevented from disclosing such information. You are entitled to see the personal data held about you. If you wish to do this, please contact us using the contact details provided below. 

Accuracy:  
We aim to keep your personal data accurate, current, and complete. We encourage you to contact using the details provided below to let us know if any of your personal data is not accurate or changes, so that we can keep your personal data up-to-date. 

Objecting:  
In certain circumstances, you also have the right to object to processing of your personal data and to ask us to block, erase and restrict your personal data. If you would like us to stop using your personal data, please contact us using the details provided below. 

Porting:  
You have the right to request that some of your personal data is provided to you, or to another data controller, in a commonly used, machine-readable format. 

Erasure:  
You have the right to erasure your personal data when the personal data is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected, or when, among other things, your personal data have been unlawfully processed. 

Complaints:  
If you believe that your data protection rights may have been breached, you have the right to lodge a complaint the applicable supervisory authority or to seek a remedy through the courts. 

You may, at any time, exercise any of the above rights, by writing to the e-mail address dataprotection@boutique1.com, together with a proof of your identity, i.e. a copy of your ID card, or passport, or any other valid identifying document.

Right to withdraw consent

If you have provided your consent to the collection, processing and transfer of your Personal Data, you have the right to fully or partly withdraw your consent. To withdraw your consent please follow the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or send an email to dataprotection@boutique1.com

How Long We Keep Your Personal Data

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for (e.g. online registration, marketing purposes, site security purposes, performing a contract or for a survey) including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements and, where required for Boutique 1 to assert or defend against legal claims, until the end of the relevant retention period or until the claims in question have been settled. 

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. 

If you want to learn more about our specific retention periods for your personal data established in our retention policy you may contact us at customercare@boutique1.com. 

Upon expiry of the applicable retention period we will securely destroy your Personal Data in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.

Cookies

Cookies are small data files that contain a string of characters. Our servers, or those of the partners we work with, may send your device a cookie when you visit the Site. Cookies help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalised service, for instance by storing information about your preferences and allowing us to recognise you when you return to our Site. 

You can find more information about cookies at: www.allaboutcookies.org. 

Our Site uses the following types of cookies: 

Strictly Necessary Cookies: These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the Site and use their features, such as accessing secure areas of the Site. Without these cookies, services like enabling appropriate content based your type of device cannot be provided. The expiry date for strictly necessary cookies is 13 months. 

Performance Cookies: These cookies collect information about how visitors use the Site, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don’t collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how the Site work. The expiry date for performance cookies is 13 months.

Functionality Cookies: These cookies allow our web servers to respond to your actions on the website such as 'Add to bag', ‘Currency’, ‘Location Preference’ or browsing the website. The Boutique 1 website wouldn’t work correctly without this. The expiry date for strictly necessary cookies is 13 months. The expiry date for functionality cookies is 13 months. 

Targeting/Advertising Cookies: Boutique1.com uses retargeting, which helps to make our online offer more interesting for customers. Retargeting technology means we can advertise recently viewed and related products on our partners' websites, meaning our adverts, even those on other companies' websites, are relevant to what customers would like to see. Boutique1.com does this by analysing user behaviour from data collected through the use of cookies. Please be assured that this kind of information is strictly anonymous and does not involve the storing of customers' personal information, or the creation of user profiles. 

From time to time, Boutique 1 will advertise on third-party websites. Cookies are used to help us and our advertisers see which advertisements customers click on and interact with. Each individual advertiser uses its own tracking cookies and the data taken from these is not confidential or interchangeable. Examples of these advertisers include Google (including Google-owned DoubleClick for paid advertising on Google.com) and LinkShare. The expiry date for targeting/advertising cookies is 13 months. 

We require your consent for cookies to be placed on your device as you visit our Site. If you don’t want to allow cookies at all, or only want to allow use of certain cookies, please refer to your browser settings. 

You can also use your browser settings to withdraw your consent to our use of cookies at any time and delete cookies that have already been set. The website www.allaboutcookies.org contains comprehensive information about the process of opting out on different browsers. 

Note that by disabling certain categories of cookies, you may be prevented from accessing some features of our site or certain content or functionality may not be available. 

If you are in the EU and would like to opt out of third party cookies relating to behavioural advertising, please go to www.youronlinechoices.eu. Opting out does not mean you will no longer receive online advertising. It does mean that the company or companies from which you opted out will no longer deliver ads tailored to your web preferences and usage patterns. 

If you have queries about our use of cookies, you can contact customercare@boutique1.com.

Changes to our Privacy Policy

We will update and change this Policy from time to time in order to reflect any changes to the way in which we process your personal data or changing legal requirements. Any changes we may make to our Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to this Policy.

Contact Details

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to customercare@boutique1.com or send a letter to Boutique 1, 259a Pavilion Road, London, SW1X 0BP. 

If you have unresolved concerns you also have the right to complain to EU data protection authorities. The relevant data protection authority will be the data protection authority of the country: (i) of your habitual residence; (ii) of your place of work; or (iii) in which you consider the alleged infringement has occurred.
